<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE ProtocolDescription SYSTEM "ProtocolDescription.dtd">

<!-- transform this xml into html (so you can view it in a browser): -->
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="ProtocolDescription_xml2html.xsl"?>

<ProtocolDescription>

  <Intro>
  <p>
  <i>NOTE: This document is available in a HTML form at the following address:
  <url>http://springrts.com/dl/LobbyProtocol/</url></i>
  </p>

  <h3>Introduction</h3>
  <p>
  This is a simple text protocol in a "human readable form". I decided for text protocol since
  it's easier to debug and implement on the client side. It does require some more overhead,
  but since server and clients do not communicate much anyway, this is not an issue. What
  really eats the bandwidth is the game itself, not lobby.
  </p>

  <h3>Nomenclature</h3>
  <p>
  We use two terms for "clients": <i>client</i> and an <i>user</i>.
  At first, <i>user</i> was considered to be a registered client,
  that means a client that is logged-in.
  The two terms are used uncleanly though, so you may best think of them as equal.
  </p>
  <h4>Legend</h4>
  <p>
  <ul>
    <li>{} = sentence = several words (at least one!) separated by space characters</li>
    <li>{} {} ... = two or more sentences. They are separated by TAB characters.</li>
    <li>words are always separated by space characters.</li>
    <li>| = separates choices ("OR")</li>
    <li>[] = denotes an optional argument</li>
  </ul>
  </p>

  <h3>Protocol low-level format rules</h3>
  <p>
  Single word arguments are separated by spaces,
  "sentences" (a sentence is a series of words separated by spaces, denoting a single argument)
  are separated by TABs.
  Make sure to replace all TABs in your sentences with spaces (2 or 8 usually)!
  If you do not, your command is invalid, and will not be read correctly by the server.
  </p>
  <p>
  Lines sent and received may be of any length. It has been tested with 600 KB
  long strings and it worked in both directions. Nevertheless, commands like
  "CLIENTS" still try to divide data into several lines, just to make sure the
  client will receive them. Since the Delphi lobby client (TASClient) now
  supports lines of any length, dividing data into several lines is not needed
  anymore. Though, we keep it just in case, to be compatible with other clients
  which may emerge in the future. I do not divide data when sending info on
  battles and clients in battles. This lines may get long, but not longer than a
  couple of hundred bytes (they should always be under 1 KB in length).
  </p>

  <h3>Protocol rules</h3>
  <p>
  A client must maintain a constant connection with the server.
  That is if no data is to be transfered,
  the client must send <clink name="PING"/> commands to the server on regular intervals.
  This ensures that the server can properly detect any network timeouts/disconnects.
  The server will automatically disconnect a client
  if no data has been received from it within a certain time period.
  A client should send some data at least after half that interval passed.
  </p>
  <p>
  Clients may find out whether a battle is in progress or not
  by monitoring the battle-founder's status.
  If his status changes to "in game", the battle's status is also "in game".
  </p>
  <p>
  A client's status and battle status are assumed to be 0 if not specified otherwise.
  Each client should assume that every other client's status and battle statuses are 0
  if not stated otherwise by the server.
  So when a client joins the server, he is notified about statuses of those users only,
  who have status or battle status different from 0.
  This way we also save some bandwidth
  (although that is not really an issue here.
  If we were worried about this protocol taking up too much bandwidth,
  we would not use a text protocol, would we?).
  </p>
  <p>
  Most of the commands that notify about some changes are forwarded to the source of the change too.
  For example: When a client sends a <clink name="MYBATTLESTATUS"/> command,
  the server sends a <clink name="CLIENTBATTLESTATUS"/> command to all users in the battle,
  including the client who sent the <clink name="MYBATTLESTATUS"/> command.
  This is a good practice, because this way the client can synchronize
  his local status with the server's, after the server has actually updated
  his status (it also serves as confirmation mechanism).
  </p>
  <p>
  All commands except for some admin specific commands are listed here.
  For more details on a specific command,
  you may have a look at a lobby servers source code,
  for example SpringLS or ueberserver.
  </p>
  <p>
  A Client may participate in only one battle at the same time. If he is hosting
  a battle, he may not participate in other battles at the same time. The server
  checks for that automatically.
  </p>
  <p>
  Team colors are currently set by players, perhaps it would be better if only
  the host would be able to change them?
  </p>
  <h4>Messages IDs</h4>
  <p>
  As of version 0.33, the command syntax has been slightly changed.
  Messages may now contain IDs:
  Any message may be prefixed with a message ID.
  For example:
  "#123 SAY main hello!" <br/>
  Server will use this ID with a reply, for example:
  "#123 SAID main Betalord hello!" <br/>
  The message ID has only one function: to ease tracking server responses for the client.
  Using message IDs means that the client can also use synchronous communication (with certain commands),
  which makes it easier to implement commands that require multiple responses in both directions.
  <br/>
  Note that IDs should be non-negative values, in a 31-bit range (0..2147483647).
  Negative values are reserved for internal handling logic of the server / lobby clients.
  </p>


  <p>
  <h3>Sub-systems</h3>
  </p>

  <h4>Syncing</h4>
  <p>
  To be in sync means, to have the same versions of all the content
  required to play a game.
  It works by clients comparing host's hash code with their own. If the two
  codes match, client should update his battle status and this way telling other
  clients in the battle that he is synced (or unsynced otherwise). The hash code
  comes from hashing the mod's file and probably all the dependences too. See
  unitsync documentation for details.
  </p>

  <h4>Hole punching</h4>
  <p>
  <quote>
  Hole punching is a computer networking technique
  for establishing communications between two parties in separate organizations
  who are both behind restrictive firewalls.
  </quote>
  <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hole_punching</url>

  We use it for allowing clients to connect to the lobby server,
  that would otherwise not be able to.

  This will probably not work in LAN mode, especially if combined with
  players from the internet.
  </p>
  <h5>Non-host perspective</h5>
  <p>
  When joining a battle, a client should first acquire his UDP source port
  from the server before sending the <clink name="JOINBATTLE"/> command.
  Once he has done that and joined the battle,
  he should keep sendings some UDP packets to the server on regular intervals,
  just to make sure the router does not forget about it and remove it
  from its translation table
  (some routers have timeout as short as 20 seconds,
  so this should also be the minimum refresh interval).
  Once the game actually starts,
  the client lobby should stop sending UDP packets to the server
  since the OS will not allow it anyway
  (will not be able to bind the same source port,
  as it will already be bound by spring.exe).
  Also, there is no need for it,
  since spring.exe will keep sending the packets
  and so keep the port open instead of the lobby client.
  Once the lobby client detects the user has returned from the game,
  it should start sending the UDP packets again,
  in order to keep the "connection" alive.
  Another thing to note is,
  that the lobby client does not need to "punch through"
  like it has to when hosting, since spring.exe will do that anyway.

  Just before starting the game,
  the server will send a <clink name="HOSTPORT"/> command to the user,
  containing the host's public UDP source port.
  The lobby cient should replace the battle's port with this one,
  as it will have to connect to this port and not the original one
  (acquired through the <clink name="BATTLEOPENED"/> command).
  </p>
  <h5>Host perspective</h5>
  <p>
  Before sending the <clink name="OPENBATTLE"/> command,
  the host should try to acquire his UDP source port from the server,
  just to make sure it can acquire it at all
  (better to find out it does not work before hosting,
  than right before starting the game).
  Nevertheless, the lobby client does not need to keep to refresh this port,
  since it will not be used to actually host the game.
  It is just a test to see if it works,
  not to actually acquire a port for hosting.
  Each time a new client joins the battle,
  the server will send a <clink name="CLIENTIPPORT"/> command,
  telling the host about this client's public UDP source port.
  The host should remember this information,
  as he will have to use it when starting the game.
  Right before starting the game,
  the host should try to acquire his source port again.
  This time he will actually use this port to host the game.
  Upon starting the game,
  the server will notify all clients participating in his battle about his port,
  using the <clink name="HOSTPORT"/> command.
  The host does not need to keep refreshing his connection
  to keep the port open,
  as spring.exe will do that for him.
  Also, upon returning from the game,
  he does not need to start refreshing it either
  (as a non-host would have to),
  since when he will start a new game,
  he will have to acquire a new source port anyway.
  This is mostly because some people could play "single-player" games with bots
  before opening the battle to other players,
  and spring.exe would of course not keep the connection alive in that case,
  and upon returning from the game,
  the port would already be timed-out long ago.
  This is why the host has to acquire a new port each time it starts a battle.
  </p>

  <h4>Match-Making</h4>
  <p>
  With match-making, we mean a somewhat abstract way of automating
  the process of users finding to each other in battle rooms
  to play a game of a type they like.

  For us this means, more specifically,
  that users get shuffled around hosts (usually autohosts) that support match-making,
  according to preferences they set, by the hand of a central match planning strategy/algorithm.
  Match-making enabled hosts have to be marked as such.
  The current way of doing this is, to let them report a CPU frequency of 6667.
  This way, each lobby client may choose to visually outline this host property
  in a certain way or not at all.
  A user may choose to take part in match-making by entering one of these hosts battle.
  When a match-maker sends a request for a certain user to switch hosts
  by sending a <clink name="FORCEJOINBATTLE:client"/> command to the server,
  and the server subsequently sends a <clink name="FORCEJOINBATTLE:server"/>
  to that addressed user,
  the lobby client must comply by joining that hosts battle-room.
  To opt-out of the match-making process,
  a user has to leave the battle-room,
  after then he may join a non-match-making enabled host.
  If the <clink name="FORCEJOINBATTLE:client"/> request was illegitimate,
  the server will send <clink name="FORCEJOINBATTLEFAILED:server"/>
  to the command issuing user.
  </p>

  <h5>Decoupling games from battle-rooms</h5>
  <p>
  For better match-making, you may now use the commands
  <clink name="CONNECTUSER:client"/> (client) and <clink name="CONNECTUSER:server"/> (server).
  They allow to initiate games without creating a battle-room first.
  That means in practise, that we can also initiate multiple games from a single chat-room.
  </p>

  <h5>Inter-lobby-client data exchange</h5>
  <p>
  For quasi direct communication between lobby clients,
  in order to allow faster development cycles,
  and to keep the lobby protocol from getting bloated unnecessarily,
  a new set of commands was introduced.
  They mirror most of the chat commands,
  but instead of human, user2user chat interaction,
  these are meant for programmatic, client2client or user2client communication.
  The server just routes the messages to the intended receiving client(s).
  They are meant to be used for stuff like standardized auto-host commands,
  for example a common set of commands and arguments for voting.
  Commands that may be used through this new communication channel
  have to be discussed and approved by the lobby-dev meeting first,
  and be documented in the <i>Inter-lobby-client data exchange protocol</i>.
  When receiving messages through these new lobby protocol commands,
  clients should generally not show them to the user as is,
  but either ignore them,
  or act according to the <i>Inter-lobby-client data exchange protocol</i>.
  <ul>
    <li><clink name="SAYDATA:client"/></li>
    <li><clink name="SAIDDATA:server"/></li>
    <li><clink name="SAYDATAPRIVATE:client"/></li>
    <li><clink name="SAIDDATAPRIVATE:server"/></li>
    <li><clink name="SAYDATABATTLE:client"/></li>
    <li><clink name="SAIDDATABATTLE:server"/></li>
  </ul>
  </p>

  </Intro>

  <RecentChanges>
  <p>

  <b><u>Version 0.38:</u></b><br/>
  <ul>
    <li>Added the OPENBATTLEEX client command.</li>
    <li>Added the BATTLEOPENEDEX server command.</li>
    <li>
    <i>Compatibility-Flags</i>
    <p>
    <ul>
      <li><b>eb</b>: deprecated: Two new arguments ( 'Engine Name', 'Engine Version' ) between 'Map Hash' and 'Map Name' for BATTLEOPENEDEX and OPENBATTLEEX commands</li>
      <li><b>cl</b>: removed REQUESTUPDATEFILE, removed OFFERFILE, removed BATTLEOPENEDEX, OPENBATTLEEX,
       moved Engine Name / Engine Version to the <clink name="BATTLEOPENED:server" />/ <clink name="OPENBATTLE:client"/> and
       made them sentences again, cl is mutal exclusive to eb.
      </li>
    </ul>
    </p>
    </li>
  </ul>

  <b><u>Version 0.37:</u></b><br/>
  <ul>
    <li>Added basic match-making system support,
      see the <i>Match-Making</i> section in the beginning of this document.</li>
    <li>Added the SAYDATA* command set,
      see the <i>Inter-lobby-client data exchange</i>
      section in the beginning of this document.</li>
    <li>An email address can now be associated with existing and set while registering an user account,
      thereby enabling unassisted account recovery</li>
    <li>Added the <clink name="FORCEJOINBATTLE:client"/> client command.</li>
    <li>Added the <clink name="FORCEJOINBATTLE:server"/> server command.</li>
    <li>Added the <clink name="FORCEJOINBATTLEFAILED:server"/> server command.</li>
    <li>Added the <clink name="LISTCOMPFLAGS:client"/> client command.</li>
    <li>Added the <clink name="COMPFLAGS:server"/> server command.</li>
    <li>Added the <clink name="CONNECTUSER:client"/> client command.</li>
    <li>Added the <clink name="CONNECTUSER:server"/> server command.</li>
    <li>Added the <clink name="CONNECTUSERFAILED:server"/> server command.</li>
    <li>Added the <clink name="SAYDATA:client"/> client command.</li>
    <li>Added the <clink name="SAIDDATA:server"/> server command.</li>
    <li>Added the <clink name="SAYDATAPRIVATE:client"/> client command.</li>
    <li>Added the <clink name="SAIDDATAPRIVATE:server"/> server command.</li>
    <li>Added the <clink name="SAYDATABATTLE:client"/> client command.</li>
    <li>Added the <clink name="SAIDDATABATTLE:server"/> server command.</li>
    <li>Added the <clink name="CHANGEEMAIL:client"/> client command.</li>
    <li>Added the <clink name="RECOVERACCOUNT:client"/> client command.</li>
	<li>Added the <clink name="EXIT:client"/> client command.</li>
	<li>Added the <clink name="GETINGAMETIME:client"/> client command.</li>
    <li>
    <i>Compatibility-Flags</i>
    <p>
    This list explains the current compatibility flags a client may send
    with the <clink name="LOGIN:client"/> command.
    This list will be emptied whenever a new protocol version gets released.
    They denote that the client supports:
    <ul>
      <li><b>a</b>: account IDs sent in the <clink name="ADDUSER"/> command</li>
      <li><b>b</b>: the battle authorization system
        (<clink name="JOINBATTLEREQUEST"/>, <clink name="JOINBATTLEACCEPT"/>
        and <clink name="JOINBATTLEDENY"/> commands)</li>
      <li><b>sp</b>: the scriptPassword parameter, sent in the
        <clink name="JOINEDBATTLE"/> command</li>
      <li><b>m</b>: the basic match-making command
        <clink name="FORCEJOINBATTLE:server"/></li>
      <li><b>cu</b>: <clink name="CONNECTUSER:server"/> command
        (for decoupling games from battle-rooms)</li>
    </ul>
    </p>
    </li>
  </ul>

  <b><u>Version 0.36:</u></b><br/>
  <ul>
    <li>'scriptPassword' argument added: This change affects the following commands:
        <clink name="LOGIN"/>, <clink name="JOINBATTLE"/>, <clink name="JOINEDBATTLE"/>.</li>
  </ul>

  <b><u>Version 0.35:</u></b><br/>
  <ul>
    <li>'serverMode' argument has been added to the <clink name="TASSERVER"/> command.</li>
    <li>Added <clink name="SETSCRIPTTAGS"/> command. This command replaces UPDATEBATTLEDETAILS command.</li>
    <li>Added <clink name="REMOVESCRIPTTAGS"/> command, companion to <clink name="SETSCRIPTTAGS"/>.</li>
    <li>New startpos type added: "choose before battle" (type 3). These change affects following commands:
        <clink name="OPENBATTLE"/>, <clink name="JOINBATTLE"/>.</li>
    <li>Added two more in-game ranks, one at 300h, the other at 1000h.</li>
    <li>Removed UPDATEBATTLEDETAILS command as it is no longer needed (use <clink name="SETSCRIPTTAGS"/> instead).
        Also removed several arguments from <clink name="JOINBATTLE"/> and <clink name="OPENBATTLE"/> commands (all these
        arguments are handled via <clink name="SETSCRIPTTAGS"/> command now). See descriptions of these commands for more info.</li>
  </ul>

  <b><u>Version 0.34:</u></b><br/>
  <ul>
    <li>Message/command ID system has been implemented to automatically (and transparently) support any
        command regardless of the method handler implementation. This means that the response to any command
        will always contain message ID if you specifed it with the original command.</li>
    <li><clink name="PING"/> command no longer supports 'key' argument since it is not needed anymore (use message ID instead)</li>
    <li>Lobby programs should now acquire Spring version via unitsync.dll and not by running spring.exe, although
        both ways are legal.</li>
    <li><clink name="LOGIN"/> command now accepts additional parameter 'userID', which is optional. See the <clink name="LOGIN"/> command description
        for more info.</li>
    <li>Added <clink name="ACQUIREUSERID"/> and <clink name="USERID"/> commands. See documentation bellow for further details.</li>
    <li>Added 'url' parameter to <clink name="SERVERMSGBOX"/> command.</li>
    <li>Added lineage mode to "end game condition" parameter (which is used with several commands).</li>
  </ul>

  <b><u>Version 0.33:</u></b><br/>
  <ul>
    <li><clink name="TASSERVER"/> command has been modified, see documentation bellow for further details.
        Note that clients should now acquire local Spring version by running "spring.exe --version"
        (they need this info to compare local Spring version to the server's).</li>
    <li><clink name="REQUESTUPDATEFILE"/> command has been modified, see documentation bellow for further details</li>
    <li>Note that MsgIDs (as described in the "Introduction" part) aren't fully supported yet - server will
        parse IDs, but won't include them in the response.</li>
  </ul>

  </p>
  </RecentChanges>

  <CommandList>

    <Command Name="PING" Source="client">
      <Description>
      The client should send this command every ~30 seconds,
      to maintain a constant connection to the server.
      The server will assume a timeout occured if it does not hear from
      the client for more than 60 seconds.
      To figure out how long a it takes a reply to from the server to the client,
      use a message ID with this command.
      </Description>
      <Response>
      See <clink name="PONG"/>.
      </Response>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="PONG" Source="server">
      <Description>
      Used as a response to a <clink name="PING"/> command.
      You can determine how long the reply took
      by using a message ID with the <clink name="PING"/> command.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="TASSERVER" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="protocolVersion" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        This is the lobby protocol version used by the server.
        The client may check if it supports this version before attempting to log in.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="springVersion" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Beginning with Spring release 89 this will be the full version string, including the latest patchlevel, 
        for example "89.0" or "101.2".
        The client should check if it has this Spring version before attempting to log in. 
        If it does not find an exact match, but a compatible version (ie. "springVersion" is 101.2 but the
        client has 101.1) is available, the client can choose to use that instead.
        <br/>
        Note that if the value of this parameter is "*",
        the client should simply ignore it since this means that
        the server does not contain any updates nor does it require latest Spring version
        (this is usually the case when the server is running in LAN mode).
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="udpPort" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        This is server UDP port where the "NAT Help Server" is running.
        This is the port to which clients should send their UDP packets
        when trying to figure out their public UDP source port.
        This is used with some NAT traversal techniques (e.g. "hole punching").
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="serverMode" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Tells what mode the server is in.
        Currently valid are:
        <ul>
          <li>0 - normal mode</li>
          <li>1 - LAN mode</li>
        </ul>
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      This is the first message (i.e. "greeting message") that a client receives
      upon connecting to the server.
      </Description>
      <Examples>
        <Example>TASSERVER 0.35 0.72b1 8201 0</Example>
        <Example>TASSERVER 0.35 * 8201 0</Example>
      </Examples>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="REGISTER" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="password" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Must be sent in encoded form (MD5 hash in base-64 form).
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="email" Optional="yes" Sentence="no">
          A valid email address. Case will not be considered.
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      The client sends this command when trying to register a new account.
      Note that the client mustn't already be logged in,
      or else the server will deny his request.
      If the server is running in LAN mode, this command will be ignored.
      The optional email allows account recovery via <clink name="RECOVERACCOUNT"/>.
      </Description>
      <Response>
      The server will respond with either a <clink name="REGISTRATIONDENIED"/>
      or <clink name="REGISTRATIONACCEPTED"/> command.
      </Response>
      <Examples>
        <Example>REGISTER Johnny Gnmk1g3mcY6OWzJuM4rlMw==</Example>
      </Examples>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="REGISTRATIONDENIED" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="reason" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent to a client that has just sent a <clink name="REGISTER"/> command,
      if registration has been refused.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="REGISTRATIONACCEPTED" Source="server">
      <Description>
      Sent to a client who has just sent a <clink name="REGISTER"/> command,
      if registration has been accepted.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="RENAMEACCOUNT" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="newUsername" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Will rename the current account name to newUsername.
      The user has to be logged in for this to work.
      After the server renames the account, it will disconnect the client.
      </Description>
      <Response>
      No formal response is required,
      although the server may reply with a <clink name="SERVERMSG"/> command.
      </Response>
      <Examples>
        <Example>RENAMEACCOUNT Johnny2</Example>
      </Examples>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="CHANGEPASSWORD" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="oldPassword" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="newPassword" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Will change the password of the users's account.
      </Description>
      <Response>
      No formal response is required,
      although the server may reply with a <clink name="SERVERMSG"/> command.
      </Response>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="CHANGEEMAIL" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="newEmail" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Will change or, in case there was none previously associated, set the email associated with a user's account.
      The optional userName may only differ from the sender name iff the sender has admin or moderator status.
      </Description>
      <Response>
      No formal response is required,
      although the server may reply with a <clink name="SERVERMSG"/> command.
      </Response>
    </Command>
    
    <Command Name="LOGIN" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="password" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Should be sent in encoded form (MD5 hash in base-64 form).
        Note that when the server is running in LAN mode,
        you can specify any username and password
        (the password will be ignored, but you must send some string anyway - you mustn't ommit it!)
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="cpu" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        An integer denoting the speed of the client's processor in MHz
        (or the value of the x+ tag if it is an AMD CPU).
        The client should leave this value at 0 if it can not figure out its CPU speed.
        <b>HACK:</b> Some lobby clients will report a <i>special value</i> instead of the processor frequency.
        This may be used by other lobby clients to display a specific icon or determine capabilities of a host.
        Known CPU identifiers are listed below:
        <ul>
          <li><i>6666</i> Springie (autohost) or Zero-K lobby client</li>
          <li><i>6667</i> Springie with match-maker enabled</li>
          <li><i>7777</i> WebLobby (web based lobby client), running at windows</li>
          <li><i>7778</i> WebLobby (web based lobby client), running at linux</li>
          <li><i>7779</i> WebLobby (web based lobby client), running mac</li>
          <li><i>-1525630178</i> MUSLCE (Android lobby client)</li>
        </ul>
        This functionality will likely be deprecated
        once there is properties suppport.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="localIP" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        The client should supply his local IP (e.g. 192.168.x.y, or whatever it uses)
        so the server can forward local IPs to clients behind the same NAT
        (this resolves some of the host/joining issues).
        If the client is unable to determine its local IP,
        he should send "*" instead.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="lobby name and version" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
        <Argument Name="userID" Optional="yes" Sentence="no">
        This is a unique user identification number provided by the client-side software.
        It should be an unsigned integer encoded in hexadecimal form (see examples).
        Note that this parameter is optional - by default it is not used/set.
        the server will send an <clink name="ACQUIREUSERID"/> command
        to tell the client that he must provide a user ID, if needed.
        However, if the lobby client program was a using user ID before,
        it should send it along with this command.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="compFlags" Optional="yes" Sentence="yes">
        When connecting, the lobby client can tell the lobby server
        that it is compatible with some optional functionalities
        that break backward compatibility.
        Each flag in this space separated parameter indicates a specific functionality
        (like IRC user/channel flags).
        By default, all the optional functionalities are considered as not supported by the client.
        For the current list of flags, see
        <i>Recent changes - Version *-SNAPSHOT - Compatibility-Flags</i>
        in the beginning of this document.
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by a client when he is trying to log on to the server.
      The server may respond with a
      <clink name="ACCEPTED"/> or <clink name="DENIED"/> command.
      Note, that if the client has not yet confirmed the server agreement,
      then server will send the agreement to the client upon receiving this command
      (the LOGIN command will be ignored; the client should resend LOGIN
      once the user has agreed to the agreement or disconnect from the server
      if the user has rejected the agreement).
      <br/>
      Also see <clink name="LOGININFOEND"/> command.
      </Description>
      <Examples>
        <Example>LOGIN Johnny Gnmk1g3mcY6OWzJuM4rlMw== 3200 192.168.1.100 TASClient 0.30</Example>
        <Example>LOGIN Johnny Gnmk1g3mcY6OWzJuM4rlMw== 3200 * TASClient 0.30</Example>
        <Example>LOGIN Johnny Gnmk1g3mcY6OWzJuM4rlMw== 3200 * TASClient 0.30<b>[TAB]</b>FA23BB4A</Example>
        <Example>LOGIN Johnny Gnmk1g3mcY6OWzJuM4rlMw== 3200 * TASClient 0.30<b>[TAB]</b>0<b>[TAB]</b>ab</Example>
      </Examples>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="ACCEPTED" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent as a response to the <clink name="LOGIN"/> command, if it succeeded.
      After the server has finished sending info about clients and battles,
      it will send a <clink name="LOGININFOEND"/> command
      indicating that it has finished sending the login info.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="DENIED" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="reason" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent as a response to a failed <clink name="LOGIN"/> command.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="EXIT" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="reason" Optional="yes" Sentence="yes">
        Clients may optionally specify a reason for quitting. The server is not required to use this reason in any way.
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Clients should send this as their last command before severing the connection to indicate
      a clean and deliberate disconnect. The server is not requried to acknowledge this in any way.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="LOGININFOEND" Source="server">
      <Description>
      Sent by the server, indicating that it has finished sending the login info
      (which is sent immediately after accepting the LOGIN command).
      This way, the client can figure out when the server has finished updating clients and battles info
      and can therefore figure out when the login sequence is finished.
      <br/>
      Note that sending login info consists of 4 phases:
      <ul>
        <li>sending MOTD</li>
        <li>sending list of all users currently logged on the server</li>
        <li>sending info currently active battles</li>
        <li>sending statuses of all users</li>
      </ul>
      This command is sent when the server has finished sending this info.
      </Description>
      <Examples>
      </Examples>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="AGREEMENT" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="agreement" Optional="no" Sentence="yes">
        The user agreement is sent in "Rich Text" format (.rtf file streamed via socket).
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server upon receiving a <clink name="LOGIN"/> command,
      if the client has not yet agreed to the server's "terms-of-use".
      The server may send multiple AGREEMENT commands
      (which corresponds to multiple new lines in the agreement text),
      finishing it with an <clink name="AGREEMENTEND"/> command.
      The client should send <clink name="CONFIRMAGREEMENT"/>
      and then resend the <clink name="LOGIN"/> command,
      or disconnect from the server if he has chosen to refuse the agreement.
      </Description>
      <Response>
      No response is expected until <clink name="AGREEMENTEND"/> is received.
      See that command for more info.
      </Response>
      <Examples>
      </Examples>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="AGREEMENTEND" Source="server">
      <Description>
      Sent by the server after multiple <clink name="AGREEMENT"/> commands.
      This way, the server tells the client that he has finished sending the agreement
      (this is the time when the lobby client should popup the "agreement" screen
      and wait for the user to accept/reject it).
      </Description>
      <Response>
      A <clink name="CONFIRMAGREEMENT"/> command is expected from the client
      in case the user agreed to the agreement.
      Otherwise, the client should disconnect from the server.
      </Response>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="CONFIRMAGREEMENT" Source="client">
      <Description>
      Notifies the server that the user has confirmed the agreement.
      Also see the <clink name="AGREEMENT"/> command.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="MOTD" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="message" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
       Sent by the server after the client has successfully logged in.
       The server may send multiple MOTD commands
       (each MOTD corresponds to one line, for example).
      </Description>
      <Examples>
      </Examples>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="UDPSOURCEPORT" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="port" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent as a response to a client's UDP packet
      (used with "hole punching" NAT traversal technique).
      For more info,
      see the <i>Hole punching</i> section in the beginnig of this document.
      </Description>
      <Examples>
        <Example>UDPSOURCEPORT 52361</Example>
      </Examples>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="CLIENTIPPORT" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="ip" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="port" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent to the battle's host, notifying him about another client's IP address
      and his public UDP source port.
      The host needs to know public UDP source ports of all players in his battle
      in order for the <i>Hole punching</i> technique to work.
      The IP is needed for both NAT traversal methods
      ("hole punching" and "fixed source ports").
      This command is sent to the the battle host immediately after a new user joins the battle
      (currently only if some NAT traversal technique is used).
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="HOSTPORT" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="port" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server to all clients participating in the battle
      (except for the host), notifying them about the new host port.
      This message will only be sent right before the host starts a game,
      if this battle is being hosted using "hole punching" NAT traversal technique.
      When a client receives this message,
      he should replace the battle's host port with this new port,
      so that when the game actually starts,
      he will connect to this new port,
      rather than to the port which the host selected when he initialy started the battle
      (with the <clink name="OPENBATTLE"/> command).
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SERVERMSG" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="message" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      A general purpose message sent by the server.
      The lobby client program should display it either in the chat log
      or in some kind of system log, where the user will notice it.
      Also see the <clink name="SERVERMSGBOX"/> command.
      </Description>
      <Examples>
        <Example>SERVERMSG Server is going down in 5 minutes for a restart, due to a new update.</Example>
      </Examples>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SERVERMSGBOX" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="message" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
        <Argument Name="url" Optional="yes" Sentence="yes">
        If specified, the lobby client should ask the user
        if he wants this URL to be opened in a browser window.
        The lobby client should then (once the user clicked OK)
        launch the default browser and open this URL in there.
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      The client should open the message in a dialog window
      (and not just in the console).
      Also see the <clink name="SERVERMSG"/> command.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="ADDUSER" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="country" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        A two-character country code based on ISO 3166 standard.
        See <url>http://www.iso.org/iso/en/prods-services/iso3166ma/index.html</url>
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="cpu" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        See the <clink name="LOGIN"/> command for CPU field.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="accountID" Optional="yes" Sentence="no">
        Unique ID bound to the account (can be used to track renammed accounts).
        This field is only provided if the lobby client sent the accountID compatibility flag ('a')
        in the <clink name="LOGIN"/> command.
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Tells the client that a new user joined a server.
      The client should add this user to his clients list,
      which he must maintain while he is connected to the server.
      The server will send multiple commands of this kind,
      once the client logs in,
      in order to provide the client with the list of all users currently connected.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="REMOVEUSER" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Indicates that a user disconnected from the server.
      The client should remove this user from his clients list,
      which he must maintain while he is connected to the server.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="JOIN" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="chanName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="key" Optional="yes" Sentence="no">
        If the channel is locked, the client must supply the correct key to join the channel
        (clients with access >= Account.ADMIN_ACCESS can join locked channels
        withouth supplying the key - needed for the ChanServ bot).
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by a client trying to join a channel.
      </Description>
      <Examples>
        <Example>JOIN main</Example>
        <Example>JOIN myprivatechannel mypassword</Example>
      </Examples>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="JOIN" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="chanName" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Name of the channel which the client has just joined
        (by previously sending the <clink name="JOIN:client"/> command).
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent to a client who has successfully joined a channel.
      </Description>
      <Examples>
        <Example>JOIN main</Example>
      </Examples>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="JOINFAILED" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="chanName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="reason" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent if joining a channel failed for some reason.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="CHANNELS" Source="client">
      <Description>
      Sent by a client when requesting the list of all channels on the server
      </Description>
      <Response>
      A series of <clink name="CHANNEL"/> command,
      followed by an <clink name="ENDOFCHANNELS"/> command.
      </Response>
      <Examples>
        <Example>JOIN main</Example>
      </Examples>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="CHANNEL" Source="server">
    <Arguments>
      <Argument Name="chanName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      <Argument Name="userCount" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
      Number of users in the channel.
      </Argument>
      <Argument Name="topic" Optional="yes" Sentence="yes">
      Is omited if the topic is not set for the channel.
      </Argument>
    </Arguments>
    <Description>
    Sent by the server to a client who requested the channels list
    via the <clink name="CHANNELS"/> command.
    A series of these commands will be sent to the client,
    one for each open channel.
    A series of CHANNEL commands is followed by the <clink name="ENDOFCHANNELS"/> command.
    </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="ENDOFCHANNELS" Source="server">
      <Description>
      Sent to a client who previously requested the channel list,
      after a series of <clink name="CHANNEL"/> commands (one for each channel).
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="MUTELIST" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="chanName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by a client when requesting the mute list of a channel.
      </Description>
      <Examples>
        <Example>MUTELIST main</Example>
      </Examples>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="MUTELISTBEGIN" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="chanName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server when sending channel's mute list to the client.
      </Description>
      <Response>
      0 or more <clink name="MUTELIST:server"/> commands
      and finally by a <clink name="MUTELISTEND"/> command.
      </Response>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="MUTELIST" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="mute description" Optional="no" Sentence="yes">
        The form of this argument is not prescribed
        (it may vary from version to version).
        The lobby client program should simply display it as it receives it.
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Multiple commands of this kind may be sent after a <clink name="MUTELISTBEGIN"/> command
      (or none, if the mute list is empty).
      </Description>
      <Examples>
        <Example>MUTELIST Johnny, 345 seconds remaining</Example>
        <Example>MUTELIST rabbit, indefinite time remaining</Example>
      </Examples>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="MUTELISTEND" Source="server">
      <Description>
      Sent by the server after it has finished sending the list of mutes for a channel.
      Also see the <clink name="MUTELIST:server"/> and <clink name="MUTELISTBEGIN"/> commands.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="CHANNELTOPIC" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="chanName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="author" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="changedTime" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Time in milliseconds since Jan 1, 1970 (UTC).
        Divide by 1000 to get unix time.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="topic" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent to a client who just joined the channel,
      if some topic is set for this channel.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="CHANNELTOPIC" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="chanName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="topic" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent a by privileged user who is trying to change a channel's topic.
      Use "*" as topic if you wish to remove the topic.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="CLIENTS" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="chanName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="clients" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent to a client who just joined the channel.
      Note: Multiple commands of this kind can be sent in a row.
      The server takes the list of clients in a channel,
      separates it into several lines and sends each line seperately.
      This ensures no line is too long,
      because the client may have some limit set on the maximum line-length
      and it could ignore the line if it was too long.
      Also note, that the clients user-name is sent in this list too!
      So when the client receives a JOIN command,
      he should not add his name in the client list of the channel,
      but he should wait for the CLIENTS command,
      which will contain his name too
      and he will add himself automatically then.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="JOINED" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="chanName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent to all clients in a channel (except the new client)
      when a new user joins the channel.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="LEAVE" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="chanName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by a client when he is trying to leave a channel.
      When the client is disconnected,
      he is automatically removed from all channels.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="LEFT" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="chanName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="reason" Optional="yes" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server to all clients in a channel when some client left this channel.
      WARNING:
      The server does not send this command to a client that has just left a channel,
      because there is no need to,
      as the client who has left the channel knows that already.
      A client that was kicked from the channel is notified about it
      via the <clink name="FORCELEAVECHANNEL:server"/> command.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="FORCELEAVECHANNEL" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="chanName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="reason" Optional="yes" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by a client (moderator),
      requsting that a user be removed from the channel.
      The user will be notified with a
      <clink name="FORCELEAVECHANNEL:server"/> command.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="FORCELEAVECHANNEL" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="chanName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="reason" Optional="yes" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent to a user who has just been kicked from the channel #chanName
      by user "userName".
      The lobby client should now internally close/detach from the channel,
      as he was removed from the clients list of #channame on the server side.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="CHANNELMESSAGE" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="chanName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="message" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server to all clients in a channel.
      Used to broadcast messages in a channel.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SAY" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="chanName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="message" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Send a chat message to a specific channel.
      The client has to join the channel first,
      to be allowed to use this command.
      </Description>
      <Response>
      See <clink name="SAID:server"/>.
      </Response>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SAID" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="chanName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="message" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent to all clients participating in a specific channel
      when one of the clients sent a chat message to it
      (including the author of the message).
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SAYEX" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="chanName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="message" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by any client when he is trying to say something in "/me" IRC style.
      Also see the <clink name="SAY:client"/> command.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SAIDEX" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="chanName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="message" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server when a client said something
      using the <clink name="SAYEX:client"/> command.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SAYPRIVATE" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="message" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Send a private chat message to an other client.
      </Description>
      <Response>
      See <clink name="SAYPRIVATE:server"/>.
      </Response>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SAIDPRIVATE" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="message" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Indicates that a user sent a private chat message to the receiving client.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="OPENBATTLE" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="type" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Can be 0 or 1 (0 = normal battle, 1 = battle replay)
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="natType" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        NAT traversal method used by the host.
        Must be one of:
        0: none
        1: Hole punching
        2: Fixed source ports
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="password" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Must be "*" if founder does not wish to have password-protected game.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="port" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="maxPlayers" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="hashCode" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        A signed 32-bit integer (acquired via the unitsync library).
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="rank" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="mapHash" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        A signed 32-bit integer (acquired via the unitsync library).
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="engineName" Optional="no" Sentence="yes">For example: 'my spring spring'</Argument>
        <Argument Name="engineVersion" Optional="no" Sentence="yes">For example: '94.1.1-1062-g9d16c2d develop'</Argument>
        <Argument Name="map" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
        <Argument Name="title" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
        <Argument Name="modName" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the client when he is trying to open a new battle. ( Compatibility-Flag need: 'eb' )
      The client becomes a founder of this battle, if the command is successful.
      </Description>
      <Response>
      The cient is notified about this command's success
      via the <clink name="OPENBATTLE:server"/> /<clink name="OPENBATTLEFAILED:server"/> commands.
      </Response>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="OPENBATTLE" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="battleID" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent to a client who previously sent a <clink name="OPENBATTLE:client"/> command,
      if the client's request to open a new battle has been approved.
      If the server rejected the request,
      the client is notified via the <clink name="OPENBATTLEFAILED"/> command.
      The server first sends a <clink name="BATTLEOPENED"/>, then this command
      (this is important - the client must have the battle in his battle list
      before he receives this command!).
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="BATTLEOPENED" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="battleID" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="type" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Can be 0 or 1 (0 = normal battle, 1 = battle replay)
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="natType" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        NAT traversal method used by the host.
        Must be one of:
        0: none
        1: Hole punching
        2: Fixed source ports
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="founder" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Username of the client who started this battle.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="ip" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="port" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="maxPlayers" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="passworded" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        A boolean - must be "0" (meaning false) or "1"!
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="rank" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="mapHash" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        A signed 32-bit integer as returned from (acquired via the unitsync library).
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="engineName" Optional="no" Sentence="yes">For example: 'my hacked spring'</Argument>
        <Argument Name="engineVersion" Optional="no" Sentence="yes">For example: '94.1.1-1062-g9d16c2d develop'</Argument>
        <Argument Name="map" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
        <Argument Name="title" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
        <Argument Name="modName" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server to all registered users,
      when a new battle has been opened. ( Compatibility-Flag need: 'eb' )
      A series of instances of this command are sent to user when he logs in
      (1 command for each battle).
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="BATTLECLOSED" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="battleID" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent when the founder has closed a battle (or if he was disconnected).
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="JOINBATTLE" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="battleID" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="password" Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="scriptPassword" Optional="yes" Sentence="no">
        A random, client-generated string,
        wich will be written to script.txt by the host,
        to avoid account spoofing
        (= someone is trying to join the battle under a wrong user-name).
        If set, the password has to be set too, even if it is empty.
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by a client trying to join a battle.
      The password is an optional parameter.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="JOINBATTLE" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="battleID" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="hashCode" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        A signed 32-bit integer.
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Tells the client that he has just joined the battle successfully.
      The server will also send a series of
      <clink name="CLIENTBATTLESTATUS"/> commands after this command,
      so that the user will get the battle statuses of all the clients in the battle.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="JOINBATTLEREQUEST" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="ip" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server to a battle founder,
      each time a client requests to join his battle,
      if the battle founder supports the battle authorization system
      (i.e., he provided the battle authorization compatibility flag ('b')
      in the <clink name="LOGIN"/> command).
      </Description>
      <Response>
      When the client receives this command,
      he must send either a <clink name="JOINBATTLEACCEPT"/>
      or a <clink name="JOINBATTLEDENY"/> command to the server.
      </Response>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="JOINBATTLEACCEPT" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by a client in response to a <clink name="JOINBATTLEREQUEST"/> command
      in order to allow the user to join the battle.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="JOINBATTLEDENY" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="reason" Optional="yes" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by a client in response to a <clink name="JOINBATTLEREQUEST"/> command
      in order to prevent the user from joining the battle.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="JOINEDBATTLE" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="battleID" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="scriptPassword" Optional="yes" Sentence="no">
        A random, client-generated string,
        wich will be written to script.txt by the host,
        to avoid account spoofing
        (= someone is trying to join the battle under a wrong user-name).
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server to all clients when a new client joins the battle.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="LEFTBATTLE" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="battleID" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server to all users when a client left a battle
      (or got disconnected from the server).
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="LEAVEBATTLE" Source="client">
      <Description>
      Sent by the client when he leaves a battle.
      Also sent by a founder of the battle when he closes his battle.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="JOINBATTLEFAILED" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="reason" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Tells a user that just tried to join a battle that he has been rejected.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="OPENBATTLEFAILED" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="reason" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Tells a user that just tried to open a battle that this request has been rejected.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="UPDATEBATTLEINFO" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="battleID" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="spectatorCount" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Assume that spectator count is 0,
        if battle type is 0 (normal battle)
        and 1 if battle type is 1 (battle replay),
        as the founder of the battle is automatically set as a spectator in that case.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="locked" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        A boolean ("0" (for false) or "1").
        Note that when the client creates a battle,
        the server assumes it is unlocked (by default).
        The client must make sure it uses this same default.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="mapHash" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        A signed 32-bit integer.
        See the <clink name="OPENBATTLE"/> command for more info.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="mapName" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server to all registered clients,
      telling them some of the parameters of the battle changed.
      A battle's internal changes,
      like starting metal, energy, starting position etc.,
      are sent only to clients participating in the battle
      (via the <clink name="SETSCRIPTTAGS:server"/> command).
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="UPDATEBATTLEINFO" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="spectatorCount" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="locked" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        A boolean ("0" (for false) or "1").
        Note that when the client creates a battle,
        the server assumes it is unlocked (by default).
        The client must make sure it uses this same default.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="mapHash" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        A signed 32-bit integer.
        See the <clink name="OPENBATTLE"/> command for more info.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="mapName" Optional="no" Sentence="yes">
        Must NOT contain the file extension!
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the founder of the battle,
      telling the server that some of the "external" parameters of the battle changed.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SAYBATTLE" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="message" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Send a chat message to all clients participating in a battle.
      A 'battleID' argument is not required,
      since every user can participate in only one battle at a time.
      If the user is not participating in any battle,
      receiption of this command is considered invalid
      and will therefore be ignored.
      </Description>
      <Response>
      See <clink name="SAIDBATTLE:server"/>.
      </Response>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SAIDBATTLE" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="message" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent to the participants of a battle when a client sent a chat message to it,
      using the <clink name="SAYBATTLE:client"/> command.
      A 'battleID' is not required,
      since every client knows which battle he is participating in,
      since every client may participate in only one battle at a time.
      If the client is not participating in any battle,
      he should ignore this command or raise an error.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SAYBATTLEEX" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="message" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by any client participating in a battle
      when he wants to say something in "/me" IRC style.
      The server can forge this command too
      (for example, when the founder of the battle kicks a user,
      the server uses this command to indicate what just happened).
      </Description>
      <Response>
      See <clink name="SAIDBATTLEEX:server"/>.
      </Response>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SAIDBATTLEEX" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="message" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server to all clients participating in a battle
      when the client sent the <clink name="SAYBATTLEEX:client"/> command.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="MYSTATUS" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="status" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        A signed integer in text form (e.g. "1234").
        Each bit has its meaning:
        <ul>
          <li>b0 = in game (0 - normal, 1 - in game)</li>
          <li>b1 = away status (0 - normal, 1 - away)</li>
          <li>b2-b4 = rank (see Account class implementation for description of rank) - client is not
              allowed to change rank bits himself (only server may set them).</li>
          <li>b5 = access status (tells us whether this client is a server moderator or not) - client is not
              allowed to change this bit himself (only server may set them).</li>
          <li>b6 = bot mode (0 - normal user, 1 - automated bot). This bit is copied from user's account
              and can not be changed by the client himself. Bots differ from human players in that
              they are fully automated and that some anti-flood limitations do not apply to them.</li>
        </ul>
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by a client to inform the server about his changed status.
      To figure out if a battle is "in-game",
      a client must check the in-game status of the host.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="CLIENTSTATUS" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="status" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        See the <clink name="MYSTATUS:client"/> command for possible values of this parameter.
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server to all registered clients,
      indicating that a client's status changed.
      Note that client's status is considered 0 if not indicated otherwise
      (for example, when you login,
      the server sends only statuses of those clients whose statuses differ from 0,
      to save bandwidth).
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="MYBATTLESTATUS" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="battleStatus" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
          An integer, but with limited range:
          0..2147483647 (use signed int and consider only positive values and zero)
          This number is sent as text.
          Each bit has its meaning:
          <ul>
            <li>b0 = undefined (reserved for future use)</li>
            <li>b1 = ready (0=not ready, 1=ready)</li>
            <li>b2..b5 = team no. (from 0 to 15. b2 is LSB, b5 is MSB)</li>
            <li>b6..b9 = ally team no. (from 0 to 15. b6 is LSB, b9 is MSB)</li>
            <li>b10 = mode (0 = spectator, 1 = normal player)</li>
            <li>b11..b17 = handicap (7-bit number. Must be in range 0..100). Note: Only host can
                change handicap values of the players in the battle (with HANDICAP command).
                These 7 bits are always ignored in this command. They can only be changed
                using HANDICAP command.</li>
            <li>b18..b21 = reserved for future use (with pre 0.71 versions these bits were used for team color index)</li>
            <li>b22..b23 = sync status (0 = unknown, 1 = synced, 2 = unsynced)</li>
            <li>b24..b27 = side (e.g.: arm, core, tll, ... Side index can be between 0 and 15, inclusive)</li>
            <li>b28..b31 = undefined (reserved for future use)</li>
          </ul>
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="myTeamColor" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Should be a 32-bit signed integer in decimal form (e.g. 255 and not FF)
        where each color channel should occupy 1 byte (e.g. in hexdecimal: $00BBGGRR,
        B = blue, G = green, R = red).
        Example: 255 stands for $000000FF.
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by a client to the server, telling him his battle status changed.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="CLIENTBATTLESTATUS" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="battleStatus" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        See the <clink name="MYBATTLESTATUS:client"/> command
        for possible values of this argument.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="teamColor" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Uses the same format as the one used with
        the <clink name="MYBATTLESTATUS:client"/> command.
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server to users participating in a battle
      when one of the clients changes his battle status.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="REQUESTBATTLESTATUS" Source="server">
      <Description>
      Sent by the server to a user which just opened a battle or joined one.
      This command is sent after all <clink name="CLIENTBATTLESTATUS"/>
      commands for all clients have been sent.
      This way, the user can choose a suitable team, ally-team and color,
      since he knows the battle statuses of other clients already.
      </Description>
      <Response>
      When a client receives this command,
      he has to send the <clink name="MYBATTLESTATUS"/> command to the server,
      so that the server can synchronize the battle status with the other clients.
      </Response>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="HANDICAP" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="value" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Must be in range [0, 100] (inclusive).
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the founder of the battle when changing a user's handicap value
      (which is part of his battle status).
      Only the founder can change other users handicap values
      (even they themselves ca not change it).
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="KICKFROMBATTLE" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the founder of the battle when he kicks a client out of the battle.
      The server removes the client from the battle
      and notifies him about it via the <clink name="FORCEQUITBATTLE:server"/> command.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="FORCEQUITBATTLE" Source="server">
      <Description>
      Sent to a client that just got kicked by the battle founder,
      using the <clink name="KICKFROMBATTLE"/> command.
      the client does not need to send the <clink name="LEAVEBATTLE"/> command,
      as that is already done by the server.
      The only purpose of this command,
      is to notify the client that he was kicked from the battle.
      Note that the client should close the battle internally,
      since he is no longer a part of it
      (or he can do that once he receives
      the <clink name="LEAVEBATTLE"/> command containing his user name).
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="FORCETEAMNO" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="teamNo" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the founder of a battle
      when he is trying to force some other client's team number to 'teamNo'.
      The server will update the client's battle status automatically.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="FORCEALLYNO" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="teamNo" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the founder of a battle
      when he is trying to force some other client's ally number to 'allyno'.
      The server will update the client's battle status automatically.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="FORCETEAMCOLOR" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="color" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Should be a 32-bit signed integer in decimal form (e.g. 255 and not FF)
        where each color channel should occupy 1 byte (e.g. in hexdecimal: $00BBGGRR,
        B = blue, G = green, R  = red).
        Example: 255 stands for $000000FF.
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the founder of a battle
      when he is trying to force some other client's team color to 'color'.
      The server will update the client's battle status automatically.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="FORCESPECTATORMODE" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the founder of a battle
      when he is trying to force some other client's mode to 'spectator'.
      The server will update the client's battle status automatically.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="DISABLEUNITS" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="unitName1" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Multiple units may follow, but at least one must be present in the arguments list.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="unitName2" Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="..." Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the founder of a battle,
      telling the server that he disabled one or more units.
      At least one unit name must be passed as an argument.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="DISABLEUNITS" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="unitName1" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Multiple units may follow, but at least one must be present in the arguments list.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="unitName2" Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="..." Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server to all clients in a battle except for the founder,
      telling them that some units have been added to disabled units list.
      Also see the <clink name="DISABLEUNITS:client"/> command.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="ENABLEUNITS" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="unitName1" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Multiple units may follow, but at least one must be present in the arguments list.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="unitName2" Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="..." Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the founder of the battle,
      telling the server that he enabled one or more previously disabled units.
      At least one unit name must be passed as an argument.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="ENABLEUNITS" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="unitName1" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Multiple units may follow, but at least one must be present in the arguments list.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="unitName2" Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="..." Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server to all clients in a battle except for the founder,
      telling them that some units have been removed from disabled units list.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="ENABLEALLUNITS" Source="client">
      <Description>
      Sent by the founder of a battle,
      telling the server that he enabled ALL units and,
      and is thus clearing the disabled units list.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="ENABLEALLUNITS" Source="server">
      <Description>
      Sent by the server to all clients in a battle except for the founder,
      telling them that the disabled units list has been cleared.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="RING" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by a client to the server when trying to play a "ring" sound to an other user.
      Only privileged users can ring everyone,
      although "normal" clients can ring players participating in their battle
      when they are hosting.
      </Description>
      <Response>
      See <clink name="RING:server"/>.
      </Response>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="RING" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Telling a client that a user just rang.
      As a consequence, the client should play the "ring" sound.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="REDIRECT" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="ip" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server when running in "redirection mode".
      When a client connects, the server will send him only this message
      and disconnect the socket immediately.
      The client should connect to the given IP, in that case.
      This command may be useful when the official server address changes,
      so that clients are automatically redirected to the new one.
      </Description>
      <Examples>
        <Example>
        REDIRECT 87.96.164.14
        </Example>
      </Examples>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="BROADCAST" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="message" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server when an urgent message has to be delivered to all users.
      The lobby client program should display this message either in some system log
      or in some message box (the user has to see this message!).
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="ADDBOT" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="name" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="battleStatus" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="teamColor" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Should be a 32-bit signed integer in decimal form (e.g. 255 and not FF)
        where each color channel should occupy 1 byte (e.g. in hexdecimal: $00BBGGRR,
        B = blue, G = green, R  = red).
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="ai dll" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/> <!-- FIXME outdated (at least the name) -->
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Allows a client to add a bot to the battle.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="ADDBOT" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="battleID" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        helps the client verify that the bot is meant for his battle.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="name" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="owner" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="battleStatus" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="teamColor" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Should be 32-bit signed integer in decimal form (e.g. 255 and not FF)
        where each color channel should occupy 1 byte (e.g. in hexdecimal: $00BBGGRR,
        B = blue, G = green, R  = red).
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="ai dll" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/> <!-- FIXME outdated (at least the name) -->
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Indicates that a client has added a bot to the battle.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="REMOVEBOT" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="name" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Removes a bot from the battle.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="REMOVEBOT" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="battleID" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        helps the client verify that the bot is meant for his battle.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="name" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Indicates that a bot has been removed from the battle.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="UPDATEBOT" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="name" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="battleStatus" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Similar to that of the normal client's,
        see <clink name="MYBATTLESTATUS:client"/> for more info.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="teamColor" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Should be a 32-bit signed integer in decimal form (e.g. 255 and not FF)
        where each color channel should occupy 1 byte (e.g. in hexdecimal: $00BBGGRR,
        B = blue, G = green, R  = red).
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by a client when he is trying to update the status of a bot.
      Only the bot owner and battle host may update a bot's status.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="UPDATEBOT" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="battleID" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        helps the client verify that the bot is meant for his battle.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="name" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="battleStatus" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Similar to that of the normal client's,
        see <clink name="MYSTATUS:client"/> for more info.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="teamColor" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Should be a 32-bit signed integer in decimal form (e.g. 255 and not FF)
        where each color channel should occupy 1 byte (e.g. in hexdecimal: $00BBGGRR,
        B = blue, G = green, R  = red).
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server notifying a client in the battle that one of the bots just got his status updated.
      Also see the <clink name="UPDATEBOT:client"/> command.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="ADDSTARTRECT" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="allyNo" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="left" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="top" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="right" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="bottom" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Adds a start rectangle for the 'allyno' ally team.
      Only the battle foudner may use this command.
      See lobby client implementations and Spring docs for more info on this one.
      "left", "top", "right" and "bottom" refer to a virtual rectangle that is 200x200 in size,
      where coordinates should be in the interval [0, 200].
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="ADDSTARTRECT" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="allyNo" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="left" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="top" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="right" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="bottom" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server to clients participating in a battle (except for the host).
      See lobby client implementations and Spring docs for more info on this one.
      "left", "top", "right" and "bottom" refer to a virtual rectangle that is 200x200 in size,
      where coordinates should be in the interval [0, 200].
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="REMOVESTARTRECT" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="allyNo" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Removing a start rectangle the for 'allyNo' ally team.
      Sent by the host of the battle.
      See client implementations and Spring docs for more info on this one.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="REMOVESTARTRECT" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="allyNo" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Removing a start rectangle the for 'allyNo' ally team.
      Sent to clients participating in a battle (except for the host).
      Also see <clink name="ADDSTARTRECT:client"/> command.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SCRIPTSTART" Source="client">
      <Description>
      Sent by a client who is hosting a battle replay game,
      indicating he is now sending the game script used in the original replay to the server.
      The server will then forward this script to all other participants in his battle.
      The correct sequence of commands when sending the script file is this:
      <ul>
        <li>1) SCRIPTSTART command</li>
        <li>2) multiple SCRIPT commands</li>
        <li>3) SCRIPTEND command</li>
      </ul>
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SCRIPTSTART" Source="server">
      <Description>
      Sent by the server to clients participating in a battle replay,
      indicating that ther server will now begin sending the game script
      from the original replay file.
      Also see the <clink name="SCRIPTSTART:client"/> (client) command comments.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SCRIPT" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="line" Optional="no" Sentence="yes">
        This is a line read from the replay script file.
        Use one SCRIPT command for each line!.
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by a client who previously sent a <clink name="SCRIPTSTART:client"/> command.
      Multiple commands of this type are expected after <clink name="SCRIPTSTART:client"/>,
      ending with <clink name="SCRIPTEND:client"/> as the last command in the sequence.
      Also see the <clink name="SCRIPTSTART:client"/> (client) command comments.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SCRIPT" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="line" Optional="no" Sentence="yes">
        This is a line read from the replay script file.
        Use one SCRIPT command for each line!.
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server after sending a <clink name="SCRIPTSTART:server"/> command.
      Multiple commands of this type are expected after a <clink name="SCRIPTSTART:server"/> command,
      ending with <clink name="SCRIPTEND:server"/> as the last command in the sequence.
      Also see the <clink name="SCRIPTSTART:client"/> (client) command comments.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SCRIPTEND" Source="client">
      <Description>
      Indicates the end of the game script from the battle replay.
      Also see the <clink name="SCRIPTSTART:client"/> (client) command comments.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SCRIPTEND" Source="server">
      <Description>
      Indicates the end of the game script from the battle replay.
      Also see the <clink name="SCRIPTSTART:client"/> (client) command comments.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SETSCRIPTTAGS" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="pair1" Optional="no"  Sentence="yes"/>
        <Argument Name="pair2" Optional="yes" Sentence="yes"/>
        <Argument Name="pair3" Optional="yes" Sentence="yes"/>
        <Argument Name="..."   Optional="yes" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by a client (battle host), to inform other clients about current
      battle configuration (start positions type, mod options, map options...).
      Only the battle host itself needs to write the corresponding script tags
      into script.txt, other battle clients should merely use them for display
      purposes.

      The [pair] format is "key=value can have spaces". Keys may not contain
      spaces, and are expected to use the '/' character to separate tables (see
      example).
      In version 0.35 of TASServer, the command UPDATEBATTLEDETAILS was
      completely replaced by this command.
      The list of attributes that were replaced (with example usage):
      <ul>
        <li>SETSCRIPTTAGS GAME/StartMetal=1000</li>
        <li>SETSCRIPTTAGS GAME/StartEnergy=1000</li>
        <li>SETSCRIPTTAGS GAME/MaxUnits=500</li>
        <li>SETSCRIPTTAGS GAME/StartPosType=1</li>
        <li>SETSCRIPTTAGS GAME/GameMode=0</li>
        <li>SETSCRIPTTAGS GAME/LimitDGun=1</li>
        <li>SETSCRIPTTAGS GAME/DiminishingMMs=0</li>
        <li>SETSCRIPTTAGS GAME/GhostedBuildings=1</li>
      </ul>
      Though in reality, all tags are joined together in a single command.
      Note that when specifying multiple key+value pairs,
      they must be separated by TAB characters.
      See the examples bellow.
      </Description>
      <Examples>
        <Example>SETSCRIPTTAGS GAME/MODOPTIONS/TEST=true</Example>
        <Example>SETSCRIPTTAGS GAME/StartMetal=1000<b>[TAB]</b>GAME/StartEnergy=1000</Example>
        <Example>See whitespaces: SETSCRIPTTAGS GAME/StartMetal=1000<b>[TAB]</b>GAME/StartEnergy=1000</Example>
      </Examples>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SETSCRIPTTAGS" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="pair1" Optional="no"  Sentence="yes"/>
        <Argument Name="pair2" Optional="yes" Sentence="yes"/>
        <Argument Name="pair3" Optional="yes" Sentence="yes"/>
        <Argument Name="..."   Optional="yes" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Relayed from battle host's <clink name="SETSCRIPTTAGS:client"/> message.
      A client lobby program must process these tags and apply them accordingly
      to the GUI presenting current battle configuration to the player.
      </Description>
      <Examples>
        <Example>SETSCRIPTTAGS GAME/MODOPTIONS/TEST=true</Example>
        <Example>SETSCRIPTTAGS GAME/StartMetal=1000<b>[TAB]</b>GAME/StartEnergy=1000</Example>
        <Example>See whitespaces: SETSCRIPTTAGS GAME/StartMetal=1000<b>[TAB]</b>GAME/StartEnergy=1000</Example>
      </Examples>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="REMOVESCRIPTTAGS" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="key1" Optional="no"  Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="key2" Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="key3" Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="..."  Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by a client (battle host), to inform other clients that a battle
      configuration setting has been removed (this is mainly usefull when
      changing map with map options).
      </Description>
      <Examples>
        <Example>REMOVESCRIPTTAGS GAME/MODOPTIONS/TEST1 GAME/MODOPTIONS/TEST2</Example>
      </Examples>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="REMOVESCRIPTTAGS" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="key1" Optional="no"  Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="key2" Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="key3" Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="..."  Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Relayed from battle host's <clink name="REMOVESCRIPTTAGS:client"/> message.
      A client lobby program has to remove these from the GUI presenting
      current battle configuration to the player.
      </Description>
      <Examples>
        <Example>REMOVESCRIPTTAGS GAME/MODOPTIONS/TEST1 GAME/MODOPTIONS/TEST2</Example>
      </Examples>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="TESTLOGIN" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="password" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Used to test if user-name and password are valid.
      Currently, this command is restricted to users with admin access only.
      It is meant to be used with some external server process
      to identify a user via a web login form
      and create a session cookie based on that.
      </Description>
      <Response>
      Either <clink name="TESTLOGINACCEPT"/> or <clink name="TESTLOGINDENY"/>.
      </Response>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="TESTLOGINACCEPT" Source="server">
      <Description>
      Used as a response to a <clink name="TESTLOGIN"/> command
      in case the user-name/password pair is valid.
      Use message ID to bind the response to a request.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="TESTLOGINDENY" Source="server">
      <Description>
      Used as a response to a <clink name="TESTLOGIN"/> command
      in case the user-name/password pair is not valid.
      Use message ID to bind the response to a request.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="ACQUIREUSERID" Source="server">
      <Description>
      When a client receives this command,
      he should immediately respond with a <clink name="USERID"/> command.
      If the client does not have a user ID associated yet,
      he should generate some random ID (unsigned 32 bit integer),
      and save it permanently as his user ID.
      He will then provide this user ID each time he logs on to the server
      via the <clink name="LOGIN"/> command.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="USERID" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userID" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        Must be an unsigned a 32 bit integer, in a hexadecimal form.
        </Argument>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent as response to a <clink name="ACQUIREUSERID"/> command.
      </Description>
      <Examples>
        <Example>USERID FA23BB4A</Example>
      </Examples>
    </Command>
 
    <Command Name="GETINGAMETIME" Source="client">
      <Description>
      The server replies with a <clink name="SERVERMSG:server"/> indicating the user's ingame time in minutes.
      </Description>
   </Command>

    <Command Name="FORCEJOINBATTLE" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="destinationBattleID" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="destinationBattlePassword" Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      A client may send this command if he is a battle host or a lobby moderator.
      The server will decide if they are, and send a command to the addressed user.
      See the <i>Match-Making</i> section in the beginning of this document for more details.
      </Description>
      <Response>
      See <clink name="FORCEJOINBATTLE:server"/> and <clink name="FORCEJOINBATTLEFAILED:server"/>.
      </Response>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="FORCEJOINBATTLE" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="destinationBattleID" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="destinationBattlePassword" Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent to a user specified in a previous <clink name="FORCEJOINBATTLE:client"/>
      command which was received on the server form an other client (host or lobby moderator).
      The receiving client must subsequently comply by sending a
      <clink name="JOINBATTLE:client"/> command to the server.
      See the <i>Match-Making</i> section in the beginning of this document for more details.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="FORCEJOINBATTLEFAILED" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="reason" Optional="yes" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server to the user who just sent a <clink name="FORCEJOINBATTLE:client"/> request,
      in the case of it being rejected by the server.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="LISTCOMPFLAGS" Source="client">
      <Description>
      A client may send this command after it has received <clink name="TASSERVER"/>
      to query the server for supported comp-flags that may be specified on <clink name="LOGIN"/>.
      </Description>
      <Response>
      See <clink name="COMPFLAGS:server"/>.
      </Response>
   </Command>

   <Command Name="COMPFLAGS" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="compFlag1" Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="compFlag2" Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="..." Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent as a response to a <clink name="LISTCOMPFLAGS:client"/> command.
      The server sends a list of supported comp-flags that may be specified
      by the client on <clink name="LOGIN"/>.
      </Description>
      <Examples>
        <Example>COMPFLAGS a b</Example>
        <Example>COMPFLAGS a b sp</Example>
        <Example>COMPFLAGS</Example>
      </Examples>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="CONNECTUSER" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="ipAndPort" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        This might be IP v4 or v6, and has to be in the form "IP:Port".
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="scriptPassword" Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      The client may send this command if it is a battle host or lobby moderator.
      The server will decide if they are, and send <clink name="CONNECTUSER"/> to the affected user,
      or <clink name="CONNECTUSERFAILED:server"/> to the client issuing this command.
      See the <i>Decoupling games from battle-rooms</i> section in the beginning of this document for more details.
      </Description>
      <Response>
      See <clink name="CONNECTUSER:server"/> and <clink name="CONNECTUSERFAILED:server"/>.
      </Response>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="CONNECTUSER" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="ipAndPort" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
        This might be IP v4 or v6, and has to be in the form "IP:Port".
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="scriptPassword" Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
       </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Instructs the client to connect spring to the given IP:port
      with the script password given in <clink name="CONNECTUSER:client"/>.
      See the <i>Decoupling games from battle-rooms</i> section in the beginning of this document for more details.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="CONNECTUSERFAILED" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="reason" Optional="yes" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent by the server to the user who just sent a <clink name="CONNECTUSER:client"/> request,
      in the case of it being rejected by the server.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SAYDATA" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="chanName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="message" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Send a data message to a specific channel.
      The client has to join the channel first,
      to be allowed to use this command.
      For more info, see the <i>Inter-lobby-client data exchange</i> section
      in the beginning of this document.
      </Description>
      <Response>
      See <clink name="SAIDDATA:server"/>.
      </Response>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SAIDDATA" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="chanName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="message" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent to all clients participating in a specific channel
      when one of the clients sent a data message to it
      (including the author of the message).
      For more info, see the <i>Inter-lobby-client data exchange</i> section
      in the beginning of this document.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SAYDATAPRIVATE" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="message" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Send a private data message to an other client.
      For more info, see the <i>Inter-lobby-client data exchange</i> section
      in the beginning of this document.
      </Description>
      <Response>
      See <clink name="SAIDDATAPRIVATE:server"/>.
      </Response>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SAIDDATAPRIVATE" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="message" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Indicates that a user sent a private data message to the receiving client.
      For more info, see the <i>Inter-lobby-client data exchange</i> section
      in the beginning of this document.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SAYDATABATTLE" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="message" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Send a data message to all clients participating in a battle.
      A 'battleID' argument is not required,
      since every user can participate in only one battle at a time.
      If the user is not participating in any battle,
      receiption of this command is considered invalid
      and will therefore be ignored.
      For more info, see the <i>Inter-lobby-client data exchange</i> section
      in the beginning of this document.
      </Description>
      <Response>
      See <clink name="SAIDDATABATTLE:server"/>.
      </Response>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="SAIDDATABATTLE" Source="server">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="no" Sentence="no"/>
        <Argument Name="message" Optional="no" Sentence="yes"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
      Sent to the participants of a battle when a client sent a data message to it,
      using the <clink name="SAYDATABATTLE:client"/> command.
      A 'battleID' is not required,
      since every client knows which battle he is participating in,
      since every client may participate in only one battle at a time.
      If the client is not participating in any battle,
      he should ignore this command or raise an error.
      For more info, see the <i>Inter-lobby-client data exchange</i> section
      in the beginning of this document.
      </Description>
    </Command>

    <Command Name="RECOVERACCOUNT" Source="client">
      <Arguments>
        <Argument Name="email" Optional="no" Sentence="no">
          The email address associated with a given username. Case will not be considered.
        </Argument>
        <Argument Name="userName" Optional="yes" Sentence="no"/>
      </Arguments>
      <Description>
        Sends an e-mail with account recovery information.
        If one or more accounts with the given email address (and optional userName) exists, the server sends an email
        to that address containing the associated username(s) and a means to reset the password(s). This
        could either be a new temporary password or for example a one-time-token that authorizes setting up a
        new password via some webinterface.
        If no account is found matching the given search criterias, no error is returned.
      </Description>
    </Command>
  </CommandList>

</ProtocolDescription>
